[Music]
[Applause]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se - radio dotnet se radio
brings you relevant and detailed
discussions of software engineering
topics at least once a month
su radio is brought to you by I Triple E
software magazine online at computer or
/ software welcome to a new show on
software engineering radio our topic
today are massively open online courses
my guest is dr. Schmidt and I'm the host
Michael
Daksh MIT is professor of computer
science at Vanderbilt University and is
going to teach his first massively open
online course in spring next year
welcome Doug
good afternoon Michael it's great to
talk to you again doc please give us an
overview on your involvement and
massively open online courses and how
come you are doing your first course in
spring next year so I've been teaching
courses related to software especially
software for distributed systems and
embedded systems and real-time systems
for close to 20 years now and during
that time I've I've probably taught
roughly 50 students a year in a
traditional face-to-face immersive
classroom environment so over 20 years
that's about what about thousand
students or so for a long time I've been
really fascinated with how we can
improve the way that we teach courses to
the students we meet in a face-to-face
environment but up to this point it's
really been about me devoting extra time
after class me devoting time
individually to work with them one on
one which just doesn't scale up very
well even though we're fortunate to have
a small number of students so one of the
reasons why I'm teaching this course is
to get a chance to start to learn and
experiment and prototype different
techniques for teaching my courses more
effectively by using digital learning
technologies and as it turns out there's
been a lot of really exciting
developments technologically in the
space of massively open online courses
or MOOCs over the past year or so as
people have started to use these as a
way to get a much broader
dissemination of knowledge to to the
broader community and so what I'm
planning to do here is I'm gonna be
teaching my first MOOC in early February
for six to eight weeks or so and as I do
that I had developed the course material
as I developed the various assessment
tools the online quizzes the online
programming assignments the online
grading and so on I'm not only gonna get
experienced teaching people in a
massively open model but I'm gonna take
the material I develop and then feed it
back into my immersive face-to-face
courses that I do here at Vanderbilt for
the students that I work with and I
think the exciting thing about that is
it'll give me a chance to do a more
effective job of teaching face-to-face
by taking the technologies and
approaches that we used for the massive
market and then finding a way to make
them work more in a more personalized
way for the individual students okay so
let us get get back to disseminate the
term MOOC so it stands for a massively
open online course I mean course is
clear but what is so massive about this
well so I gave you the example before of
teaching about 50 students a year for 20
years giving me about a thousand
students during my career with us thus
far in the first week of the
announcement of my MOOC course which
will be on patterns and frameworks for
concurrent and networked software I had
two thousand students in the first week
and a couple weeks into this we're now
about a month and a half or so after the
announcement I now have around ten
thousand students enrolled in my course
it would take me about a thousand years
to teach ten thousand students in my
traditional face-to-face way of doing
things and I have a feeling by the time
the course goes live in the February
time frame I'll probably have something
more like thirty to fifty thousand
students so that becomes pretty massive
by almost any definition of massive and
part of the goal part of the challenge
technologically here is to leverage
digital learning methods and tools so
that the students who take the course
but the fifty thousand students or
thirty thousand students who take the
course through distance learning get
almost the same quality and sense of
intimacy that they would get if they
were to be in my face-to-face class so
that's that's part of the massive nature
of it obviously when I teach my courses
for the
here at Vanderbilt I look at every one
of their programming assignments by hand
and I provide them with extensive
comments and then they give me back
their improved version and we use that
as the grading as the final grade for
the project when you're teaching 30 to
50,000 students there's absolutely no
way one human being even with an army of
of TA teaching assistants would be able
to keep up with that kind of volume so
we're gonna have to come up with new
approaches to automating the assessment
automating the grading automating the
quizzes automating the programming
assignments and so on so the people can
get good feedback but we can do it in a
scalable way so that's a lot of where
the massive comes from it's just the
sheer number of people involved and then
the next term it's open is it open as an
open source meaning free yes this is
actually in the in the use of open in
the sense of open or free being free
beer as opposed as opposed to free
speech so the courses that we're doing
which is through the the Coursera
organization which is that consortium
about 33 top universities in the US and
around the world all the material that
they're doing in Coursera is available
for free online and we're very fortunate
that Vanderbilt University has chosen to
make the investment in both time and
resources my time and the resources of
people who will help produce the course
from a video production and editing
point of view we're very fortunate they
have agreed to do this and then we'll
make that content available literally to
anybody anywhere in the world who has
access to a computer network and a
browser effectively so that's what makes
it open and right now there are no there
are no you're not gonna be getting a
course credit from Vanderbilt from
teaching this taking this course but I
suspect over time as these things and
mature and evolve and we address issues
of how do you make sure that people
aren't cheating and you make sure that
people who are taking the course are
doing their own work and so on I suspect
you're gonna start seeing some type of
certificate program or grading or credit
being provided using this material that
we're producing as part of this exercise
and the next term would be online I mean
that is clear it's
it's an online course so we clarified
that you mentioned
casera so is it the only provider of
such MOOCs there's a number of MOOC
providers at this point some of the the
early work was done by the folks at
Stanford University and Ruane
and Daphne Koller who are the cofounders
of Coursera they came from Stanford they
were professors there and they became
the cofounders of Coursera and they're
one of the leading organizations doing
this with again roughly 33 or so
universities from around the country the
US and around the world there are also a
couple of other groups there's a group
called EDX which is Harvard University
MIT University of Berkeley and I believe
University of Texas at Austin just
joined EDX as well don't don't quote me
on that but I think they have four
organizations now and they're offering
courses there's also some other ones
that are a little bit less formal
there's the Khan Academy which is mostly
through sort of YouTube like videos
showing very specific kinds of
techniques and approaches to learning
and then there's also another group
called Udacity which as as I understand
is a for-profit organization but I
suspect we're gonna see a lot more
different business models a lot more
different approaches in this space over
the next year or two because it's a
rapidly growing ecosystem and a lot of
this is driven by the fact that as
Thomas Friedman once said about this
particular topic great breakthroughs
often occur when what is suddenly
possible meets what is desperately
necessary and trying to get a handle on
the cost of higher education on one hand
and then being able to provide good
quality education to many people all
people around the world those are two
interesting forces that have been
working for quite a long time and
because of the advances in digital
technology over the last decade and the
advances in broadband network access
we're finally at a point where many
people in fact almost everybody in the
world will have a chance to avail
themselves of a body of knowledge that
heretofore has only been available to
people in the upper ends of the the
strata people who are able to go to the
top universities in certain countries at
certain times I mean as who you
mentioned bandwidth what kind of
prerequisite would be needed for such a
course I think you typically need
basically broadband access if you've got
enough to be able to it the very least
listen to audio versions of the material
maybe you're watching slides and
listening to the audio that's probably
the bare essential most of the the
material that's produced for Coursera
and some of the other ones would also
require some video display as well but
that's probably not quite as important
as the ability to see the the slides and
listen to the audio track for the most
part the video production is is mostly
just to give you a little bit more of a
feeling of talking or listening to a
real human being as opposed to just
listening to you know books on tape kind
of a kind of a session this adjud that
it started off from the computer science
community computer science professors I
if I'm not mistaken the founders of
casera
are both professors of computer science
respectively
machine learning yes that's right they
had particular specialties that have
become extremely appealing today they
did a lot of work on things like machine
learning and data mining which of course
is you can imagine in this day and age
of search engines and search
optimization and unstructured data
analysis data analytics and so on for
for many many different purposes for
advertising for Homeland Security for
other kinds of purposes in your
knowledge knowledge learning and so on
people really had an interest in knowing
how to apply various artificial
intelligence techniques and machine
learning algorithms in order to be able
to be effective at this brave new world
of big data analytics and so they
discovered a couple years ago probably
2009 2010 that there was a demand for
the kind of courses that they were
teaching at Stanford and they had pretty
much maxed out the number of students
that could physically sit in a lecture
hall at Stanford University and get
anything useful out of the course I
think
they had roughly 400 students in the
class I think the first time they taught
the course this was probably Andrew Inge
and he had something upwards of a
hundred thousand students the first time
I taught the course online so at that
point they began to realize that there
was an amazing ability of being able to
to transform the educational experience
to give a lot more people access to
their knowledge to their material to
their expertise than they ever could
possibly afford to do in the traditional
face-to-face type of model so that's
kind of where things started they
weren't the only ones who were doing
this though there were other people I
believe it was like the Khan Academy the
guy discovered that he wanted to be able
to teach some of his family members
various types of mathematics and he was
able to use YouTube videos to instruct
them from a distance and he discovered
this was a real popular way to teach a
lot of different topics and so the work
that Khan Academy has done has really
sprung from from trying to help educate
a local community and that of course has
turned out to be a very valuable
technique to educate a broader community
as well you mentioned briefly the Brit
Assessors so what were the properties or
the disadvantages of the previous models
that resulted at the end in the MOOC
evolution and the MOOC success today
which we didn't see with the previous
methods approaches so far sure so
there's a couple of different answers to
that I think one of the things that
we've seen is that done simply doing the
the intuitive and somewhat naive
approach of taping someone giving a talk
which is the way that most people have
historically done lectures you know just
a person standing in front of a group of
people giving a lecture that approach
while it works reasonably well in a
small group environment face to face
doesn't really scale up to the the
capabilities of a massively open online
course environment so people have had to
rethink the way in which they produce
the material and we're benefited here of
course by the fact that there's now a
lot more expertise in the form of being
able to to capture voice and video
through things like Skype or
things like various editing tools you
can have on your PC or your tablet and
the ability to manipulate those things
to create fairly sophisticated intuitive
nice fun informative video production
capabilities on a budget you don't need
to have a tremendous amount of
investment to do this so so part of its
been the advance and computer editing
and and computer manipulation of voice
and video so that's that's part of it
the other thing though I think it's even
more important is access to the
expertise the expertise space the body
of knowledge that's so crucial to making
this work if if one or two people try to
come up with a set of courses they're
very good quickly going to be limited by
the scope of their expertise and while
there certainly are many many talented
people at universities who are capable
of being able to teach on interesting
subjects the problem is that they are
usually experts at us a handful of
topics but what you really need to build
a curriculum is a wide variety of topics
say the topics you would expect to find
at a top university almost anywhere in
the world where you've got many experts
so one of the things that I think the
folks that the Coursera have done a
really good job of is putting together a
team of the top professors at the top
universities around the world because
that gives them access to expertise that
gets them access to some of the most
informed and dynamic and charismatic
professors who can talk about subjects
that they know and love and have great
to be Greve experience and knowledge in
and then they can individually record
stuff that is relevant for what they do
but then collectively course Eric and
package together all that material to
give pretty much you know maybe with a
few gaps pretty much give a
comprehensive undergraduate education in
certain areas just as one example I
think at this point the Coursera
offerings for computer science are
almost sufficient that you could teach
pretty much an undergrad curriculum in
computer science that would be probably
superior to almost everything you could
imagine at most of the universities in
the world today because they're able to
tap into experts from all the top places
Wow
so is it especially suited for computer
science topics or is it also applicable
to the whole broad set of topics taught
at university well interesting enough
again speaking for Coursera I'm sure the
other groups have similar experiences
the most popular course that they have
right now is introduction to finance and
accounting for whatever reason that
course is just off the charts in terms
of interest another course that's very
popular is a course that's the history
of of the 20th century which isn't
anything at all like a typical computer
science course I think realistically
speaking at this point given the
technology we have at our disposal the
kinds of courses that work best on
Coursera fit into two categories one
there's a way of being able to do some
kind of online interactive assessment
which works pretty well if you have
multiple choice questions short answer
questions true/false questions maybe
some programming assignments and so on
but of course doesn't really work well
if you're trying to do laboratory
experiments involving chemicals or lab
animals you know you're not going to
hook those things up to your to your
computer and do anything sensible so
some of the some of the arts some of the
Arts and Sciences courses that involve a
studio model or you know experiments
that are not easily turned into cyber
interactions them are more difficult
today to do but the technology is
rapidly evolving so one of the things
that Coursera folks are able to do at
this point is they're actually able to
do peer grading for things like short
answer questions or essays that you
would expect to find in various
humanities disciplines such as as
English or literature and that was up to
this point sort of out of reach of
earlier people who tried to to do these
kinds of online assessments because they
had to have humans in the loop in almost
every place and without the massive body
of students who are willing to spend
time doing assessments of each other's
work it's very difficult to scale up the
assessment and evaluation part so I
think to answer your question in a
nutshell the computer technology has
gotten much better to be able to produce
these
these courses online in a cost-effective
way to give the right quality with the
right dynamics that are effective for
computerized learning and we now have a
way of being able to leverage the huge
body of expertise of people who were
able to teach courses that work well in
a digital environment I should also
point out one more thing that's that's
relevant in this space when people are
first confronted with the concept of
digital learning there's a tendency to
think gosh you know I remember back to
my days as an undergrad sitting in a
small seminar course being able to
involve in a in a deep discussion and
debate with my professor face to face
and and how enriching and how
stimulating that was and I can't
possibly see how watching something
videos on a computer could anywhere near
rival that degree of interactive
learning and I think when we when we
think like that we tend to perhaps
romanticize what many people's education
experiences these days an awful lot of
people when they go to college aren't
sitting in courses with a professor and
10 other students they're sitting in a
large lecture hall with with 2 to 300
other students and somebody a little
blip down on the stage is giving a talk
and the students are you know half
listening they're surfing the web
they're tweeting their various things
and text messaging each other and and
the lecture environment really isn't as
much about interactive teaching and
learning is it is about one-way flow of
information so the first thing to
remember is that that's what many people
experience these days in education the
second thing that's worth noting is that
in those kinds of environments and quite
frankly even in traditional smaller
classroom environments only a handful of
people at any given point in time only a
handful of students are actually engaged
in two-way interaction with the
professor I know that when I'm teaching
material on software patterns or
software frameworks or distributed
systems or concurrent and networked
programming I'll be lecturing and asking
questions and seeing if the students
have their thoughts to share and at any
given point in time in a class of you
know 15 to 20 people only a handful of
people will raise their hand and maybe
only one or two people will get the
question answered correctly so what's
happening there is most people are
listening hopefully they're following
along but they're not really
participating in any deep way in
contrast in a well produced digital
learning course every three to five
minutes we can pop up a question to ask
students to make sure that they've
understood what was just covered on the
previous slides and we can make sure
that every single student all 50,000 of
them taking that course has all got a
chance to answer that question and
answer the question correctly before
they're able to go on and hear the next
part of the lecture so that's what's
called that's a technique in the
pedagogy literature called mastery
learning and it turns out when you start
to do mastery learning learning the
students tend to follow along more
closely they can't make progress until
they've mastered some set of material
and as a result they're actually
potentially can be more interaction for
more students than you would typically
find in your normal face-to-face
classroom where we're only the people
who are extroverts and how they
motivated the answer questions tend to
be the ones interacting with the
professor so I think it's it's important
that we remember you know that not
everything is a seminar and even in
seminars not everybody's participating
all the time so there's a real
opportunity here through digital
learning to improve the degree of
participation of all the students not
just the ones who are most comfortable
raising their hand your topic will be on
patterns and frameworks your teaching
the class you're teaching in spring next
year what are your personal experience
is now preparing for this class do you
have to restructure and reorder all your
material well you have to change all
your programming exercises I guess for
the programming exercises yes but for
the other topics please share some some
of your insights
you bet absolutely I've been teaching
courses on on patterns and frameworks
for networking concurrent systems for
four decades now and I've got a quite a
large volume of course material on this
topic slides and and assignments and and
quizzes and so on and I've
had to rethink things quite a bit for
this class just to give you a couple
examples normally when I would if I
would teach this class normally I would
probably only focus it on a particular
programming language so for example if
I've taught the class in a distributed
real-time embedded systems context I
would probably focus on patterns and
frameworks in C++ because that's very
common in that space
conversely if I was teaching a course
maybe for smartphone developers I would
probably maybe teach it in Java the
point is that when I teach a course in a
face-to-face environment I pick a
language typically pick you know a
handful of systems to use and that's
what we do because it gets too
complicated to try to teach multiple
languages multiple systems all at the
same time when I'm doing the course for
the online version in contrast what I'm
going to be doing is I'm going to be
talking about a topic and I'll be
presenting a pattern oriented solution
to the topic first without necessarily
having to dedicate or hard-code the
discussion to a particular language to a
particular system so we can say talk
about the patterns for developing user
interfaces or we can talk about the
patterns for developing a high
performance web server etc and we can
talk about those patterns in in the
classic pattern language way we can talk
about the patterns their roles and
responsibilities the dependencies they
have on each other the way in which a
sequence of patterns can be used to
resolve certain forces in the design
space and so on and then what I can do
when I've done recording that module and
in each module is roughly fifteen to
twenty minutes long on a particular
topic then I'm going to go back and I'm
going to record different versions of
those patterns demonstrated with a
particular language with a particular
technology so we might talk about a web
system or a web server and then I would
show how you could implement that
pattern language for that particular
application using say C++ with ace and I
can record that and I can show how those
patterns are instantiated into something
concrete so people who are following
along who want to see more than just the
design aspects can actually dive down
and look at the solutions in in
code and in detailed design and if
you're a C++ developer that's probably
the path for you
conversely if you're a Java developer
I'll have a different track well you can
we can do the same thing we can show the
pattern language as its implemented in
Java and maybe we'll show one where we
might implement it in Java using say
Android so people who have a different
set of interests can follow a different
path through the material they'll all
get a chance to understand the patterns
in their more platform and language
independent way but then through the
magic of digital technology different
people can take different paths through
the course that most match their
particular needs and that is absolutely
something I've never been able to do
when I've been teaching my courses
heretofore
because we just didn't have the
resources and the time to do that so
this will be a very interesting approach
of course this this makes it a little
bit more complicated because we have to
record multiple versions of the patterns
but I think the end result is going to
be worthwhile
now just to bring this back to what we
had talked about before this is also
exciting because once I create this
material what I can do when I teach my
face-to-face class the next fall is I
can take the video content I've created
for the online version and I can put it
into something known as a flipped
classroom model and so what I can do is
I can ask my my students in my
face-to-face class of which they'll
probably be more like you know 30 to 40
as opposed to 50,000 I can ask them to
watch small 15-20 minute video modules
on the material before they show up to
class and I can make sure through the
magic of the online grading and online
assessments whether those students
actually understood what they just
watched so they'll have to fill out the
questions I'll have to do the quizzes
and so on so by the time people show up
to my actual face-to-face class I'll
have a very good idea of what they
understand what they don't understand
and how I can cover the material
face-to-face in a way that will deepen
the understanding that they got by
watching the video so that's that's
called flipping the classroom and it
allows you to spend more time in the
class in a design studio studio like
approach giving people much more
tailored
helped much more tailored response is
much more tailored input for weaknesses
you've identified because of the fact
that we've leveraged the digital
learning material ahead of time this
sounds really cool so I wish I would be
back in student days great well well the
great the great thing of course Michael
is you don't have to be a an undergrad
or a grad student anymore to leverage
this in fact the Coursera people have
found that the bulk of the demographics
that they have identified as people
taking the courses these days are
between 30 to 50 years old and so what
they're finding is many of the students
who are actually attending the courses
are working adults who are coming back
to get that specialized education that
they might not have been exposed to when
they were undergrads because technology
has moved so fast in the mean time that
the material they learned is perhaps no
longer what's being useful for the jobs
that they're being asked to do at work
cool so I mean what kind of exercises
are you selecting and what kind of
grading system did you come up with for
your course so they're basically two
different types of evaluation mechanisms
we'll be using one type is going to be
the pop-up quiz probably multiple-choice
maybe short answer where we just kind of
make sure the students have been
following along for the last five
minutes or so of the of the lecture
material you know every three or four
slides you pop up a little quiz and say
you know what was the intent of the
pattern we just covered or which of the
following are the forces that are
resolved by this particular pattern
those kinds of questions or you know
what is the definition of a framework so
you can basically make sure the students
are paying attention and not just you
know snoozing and and just basically not
really getting out of the material what
you'd hope they'd get so that that's one
approach and those can come up very
frequently at the end of every module
we'll also have some programming
assignments and again this is still kind
of a work in progress but what I hope to
be able to do is allow people to be able
to write the programming assignments in
either C++ or Java and then they'll be
able to submit them and depending on how
clever we can get in terms of our
ability to par
the submissions and grade them and
review them at the very least we can we
can review them to see if they work or
not ie they produce the right result
that's that's kind of the the easiest
thing to do and then perhaps for some of
the assignments that are in a language
like Java that's got some reflective
capabilities we can actually develop
Auto grading tools that will go in and
look for certain style or structure
mechanisms in the code as well that's a
little bit more of an ambitious thing
because that's really getting into more
of the subjective qualities and
qualitative aspects of assessment so I'm
not sure if the technology is quite
ready for that but I think looking ahead
where I see the field going over the
next few years is people using platforms
like Coursera to develop much more
sophisticated automating automated
grading techniques which of course will
work well for these large MOOC classes
as well as maybe work for the
face-to-face ones as well right now I do
that kind of work myself when I do the
pre-screening of my students assignment
submissions I go through and I'm I
basically play compiler I play you know
syntax and semantics style editor and so
on but but that takes a lot of time and
it would be nice if we could automate
that so I could really zoom in on the
things that were the really important
stuff which was understanding design
understanding optimization techniques
understanding the implementation
approaches that are not easily learned
just by reading a book I have to tell
one anecdote when I was in your research
group and I would have coded something I
would have to first show it to you of
course in the first submissions only
later it got more relaxed but on the
first submissions I saw that online
parser and online editing I was just
amazing how does lines just move back
and forth and was a great learning
exercise so I wouldn't have want to miss
that in the past thanks again for that
Oh so I know how you work yeah it's
great it's great to be able to do that
for a dozen students it's it's gonna be
a lot harder obviously to do that
manually for for thousands of them so
for the programming assignments it
we'll be difficult and we will have to
advance technology and our experiences
to do that right so we are it seems like
we are more at the beginning to create
programming assignments that's right and
I think another thing that's worth
mentioning here is is obviously the
whole issue of people doing their own
work the the one of the impediments at
the moment to a broader adoption of
online courses in mainstream education
is the concern that the people who are
submitting the work aren't the people
who are who are actually taking the
class you know you can imagine a world
where you could outsource you could have
low cost places in the world that would
do your homework for you and then they
would give you the solution you could
submit it on and so so obviously there's
a lot of capabilities there's lots of
demand for for people doing you know
various kinds of plagiarism detection
tools to detect this kind of thing and
there's been a lot of good work that's
been done for many years at various
universities around the world to do that
but now we have a context in which we
can apply it we can get tons of data we
can you know in continue to improve the
static and dynamic analysis techniques
to detect that kind of plagiarism and I
think that this is something where
technology will play a large role in
being able to solve the the issue of
ensuring that the students do their own
work and they get credit for the work
that is their work as opposed to
somebody else's work we talked already a
bit about the application of the
learnings from the online course to an
immersive learning class is there any
more about it how the learnings and
findings experience and the online
courses would benefit the classroom
students absolutely and I think a lot of
this has to do with with sample size if
you teach a class with you know 15
people in it in many of the courses at
Vanderbilt are relatively small we have
15 you know 25 students or so you have a
relatively small sample and in that
sample of course tends to be the
students that are generally pretty well
educated and and reasonably well
motivated etc so it's not always clear
you know how they are learning
what what are some stumbling blocks that
are vexing them all and and especially
if you don't have the kind of course the
design studio like course I typically
teach where I look at all the programs
you can imagine if it was a more
traditional course where people were
graded by teaching assistants only and
so on it might not be easy for a
professor to know what was confusing the
students you know what common approaches
that he or she was presenting an
immature were effective which approaches
were not effective where were people
getting confused and so on because you
have no easy mechanism other than a quiz
and a programming assignment on a
periodic basis to assess whether people
are learning conversely if you have a
hundred thousand students taking your
course and every five minutes they have
to do a quiz you find out pretty quickly
what they are understanding what they're
not understanding so if you give them a
question and you know thirty thousand
students out of your fifty thousand
students get it wrong why is that are
they don't do they not know what they're
doing
did you do a poor job of explaining it
and maybe we could come up with
techniques that would a help us to do a
better job proactively of designing our
lecture material to address these common
problems ahead of time so they wouldn't
be confusions by the time they were
tested on it or B if people miss things
in a common way it becomes possible
through data analytics and machine
learning and analysis to identify common
patterns of misconception which can then
be addressed through various hints or
other kinds of feedback we give the
students when they when they don't get
the problems right so you can certainly
imagine in in a in an online course
where you were trying to do mathematical
analysis or proofs or something and if
somebody submitted to prove or they
submitted a solution that had mistakes
in it probably wouldn't be that hard for
the computer to figure out why they were
being confused especially if thousands
of them were being confused and then be
able to give them a hint say you know
you're not quite doing the derivative
correctly or here's a different way to
think about integration under the curve
and so a computer is very patient a
computer can take forever to help people
master
their confusion a TA a professor there's
only a certain number of hours in the
day there's only a certain amount of
time in office hours you could only
spend so much time on one person so I
think what we're gonna see here is the
ability to really tailor the educational
experience for the individual students
in ways that you just can't afford to do
with the traditional immersive
environment without using these kinds of
computer-based tools one question and I
wanted to I said you'd that question in
the beginning already I mean what makes
an University what makes an expert like
you put time into a glass and offer it
for free well I think my main interest
in all of this is to help improve the
the face-to-face courses I'm teaching
for the students that are enrolled at
Vanderbilt and the fact that we can at
the same time help out hundreds of
thousands of students around the world
is just icing on the cake but but I
really see there are three ways that it
pays off to my existing employer event
about University two to give me the
opportunity to do this first of all it's
going to help the current students that
we have at Vanderbilt because we'll be
able to start applying these digital
learning techniques in a flipped
classroom environment as early as the
spring or certainly by next fall
and so they will begin to benefit from
all the stuff that we're talking about
second way it helps is it allows the
people who are alumni from Vanderbilt
people who are students here you know a
year or two ago or five years or 10
years or 20 years who are still
interested in being connected to the
Vanderbilt community they can go back
now and they can watch lectures by their
favorite professors or by people who are
experts in the field talking about
things that may be even more relevant to
what they're doing in their jobs then
they may have realized when they were
here number one and number two the the
material will have been updated and
topics we're going to cover this fall
won't have been what we covered five ten
years ago when I first came to
Vanderbilt about ten years ago I didn't
know anything about Java concurrent
network programming in android because I
didn't know any Java and Android didn't
exist so of course I didn't teach that
kind of material for a decade now it
does exist now
I've learned it now I can convey that so
my students of the past can come back
and and take a refresher from a
professor that they may have enjoyed
earlier me talking about some new stuff
and I think the third benefit that it
does for for my university is it helps
allow people all around the world
understand the kinds of material that we
cover and the quality we provide and the
depth of Education experience it can be
encountered by coming to Vanderbilt and
by doing that it helps us to attract the
best and brightest students from around
the country and around the world to want
to come here as undergrads or as
graduates so I think there's a lot of
ways in which this digital learning
methodology helps us to do a much better
job in our existing immersive
environment so I don't see it as just
you know giving away stuff for free I
see it as an investment in the future of
learning technology in immersion
ecosystems such as a place like
Vanderbilt University
can I ask you whether you yourself have
already taken a MOOC I have watched a
number of them online in preparation for
my course because I wanted to understand
the different models people were using
to present the material all the way from
just Rena recording themselves giving a
lecture with a with a you know handheld
camera to something more sophisticated
and more multimedia enriched I've also
done a couple of recordings for other
activities using MOOC like techniques so
I've got some experience developing
these things you know the techniques
that I find personally work for me how I
like to present the material and and one
of the things I'm finding more and more
and the work I do is the ability to give
webinars or podcasts like this digitally
so that we can archive them so I can
expand and reach people in far corners
of the country in far corners of the
world then I would otherwise have a hard
time getting to meet face to face so I
think of this all as a natural extension
of things that I've been doing for quite
a long time as an educator and as a
researcher but at long last we have a
platform for packaging and delivering
this material to everybody around the
world whereas before it was done in sort
of a hit-or-miss like manner
for a particular organization a
particular sponsor a particular group
now we can we can do it for everybody
where do you see this approach lead into
in five or ten years any vision about it
yeah absolutely I think it's gonna be a
bifurcated model I think there gonna be
some universities who are going to be
heavily reliant on the content for MOOCs
to either augment some gaps in their
existing curriculum or to be able to
allow them to reach the number of
students they're going to need at a cost
that is is reasonable and affordable so
you know some universities these days
are very strapped for funds a lot of
state universities have been getting
cutbacks from their state legislatures
because of the budget crisis and the
economic downturn a lot of these places
have quite a number of students that
they have to educate they don't have the
money to hire faculty to teach them all
in a face-to-face manner I think you're
gonna see a lot of the use of of MOOC
like content coupled with you know
face-to-face lectures or sort of
recitation sessions or teaching
assistants or whatnot being used to
augment and expand those kinds of
universities so that they can reach the
communities they are obligated to serve
by the virtue of the fact that they're a
state university so that's sort of one
model the other model which is kind of
more of the the Vanderbilt University
type of model the more kind of top-tier
immersive education environments the the
Stanford's Harvard's mi t--'s and
Vanderbilt and so on I see them using
this material in a slightly different
way I think they're going to use it to
to enrich the immersion experience that
they already have by the techniques we
just talked about by being able to get
access to the best people to augment the
the quality of their already great
faculty I mean let's face it everybody's
an expert everybody at a top university
is an expert in something but pretty
much nobody's an expert in everything so
I would love to be able to for example
if some of the other great people in the
world like Doug Lee
an expert on concurrent programming in
Java or Frank Bushmen or Kevin Henny or
Michael character so I'd be people who
who are great at their topics were to
talk about their expertise and record it
I would love to be able to use that
material in my classes and so it'll help
make me a more effective professor
because I don't have to be an expert at
everything I don't have to try to
pretend like I'm an expert in everything
I can leverage the expertise of those
people who've packaged their knowledge
in a readily digestible form in many
ways these types of universities are
going to be using MOOCs as essentially a
multimedia textbook so students will be
able to learn about some topic not only
by browsing the web and looking at
online documentation or reading a
textbook they'll be able to go and watch
a video by the inventor of Java or the
inventor of C++ or an expert of machine
learning or an expert in real-time
scheduling in order to augment and
deepen the knowledge that they have on a
subject so I my vision of the future is
that we'll have universities that are
you know kind of divided into these two
camps one group uses MOOCs as a way to
deepen the immersion experience the
other group is using it as a way to be
able to serve their population in an
affordable way and of course there'll be
many things in between those are just
sort of to two of the extreme the
perspectives on how I think this is
gonna unfold I think we covered the
topic really well especially with those
last verts any final words you want to
share with our listeners ah well I guess
the main thing I'd like to encourage
people to do is to start sampling the
material that's available now the
ever-growing corpus of videos and
multimedia presentations available in
the MOOC context and certainly be great
to see you in my course that's coming up
here and beginning of February on
patterns and frameworks for concurrent
network software and I look forward to
getting feedback and and other insights
from people who've who've gone through
the process and have their insights to
share back with those of us who are
trying to produce the content most
effectively okay thanks doc for sharing
your experiences with us
thank you Michael always a pleasure talk
you soon thanks thanks for listening to
SC radio an educational program brought
to you by I Triple E software magazine
for more information about the podcast
including other episodes visit our
website @ SC - radio net to support us
you can advertise su radio by clicking
the Digg reddit delicious or / side
buttons on the site or by talking about
us on Facebook Twitter or your own blog
if you have feedback specific to an
episode please use the commenting
feature on the site so that other
listeners can respond to your comments
as well this and all of the episodes of
se radio is licensed under the creative
commons two-point-five license please
see the website for details thanks again
for your support
[Music]
[Applause]